ipott.com 2012-12-29

# iPOTT - Our Privacy and Information Policy

## Did you notice something?

We keep encouraging you to register with us. We also insist upon you to provide us certain Personally Identifiable Information. We insist on providing a valid company mail id. This section is intended to give you an explanation, why we collect the information and how we use it based on our information policy? 

## Personally identifiable information

  * We require you to provide us a valid mail id during registration. We suggest you avoid free mail ids like rediff, yahoo, hotmail, etc. A generic company mail id is more appropriate. This mail id will be used for correspondence. This mail id will be displayed on the website for the 'Buyer or Seeker' to contact you.   
We will not resell this mail id to any other individual or company. It will be used only for the intended purpose, specified above and in other areas on this website. 
  * We ask you to provide information like your Company name, Logo, Address, Contact Name, E-mail, Web page URL etc., This information will be made available on our web. We will be collecting all the information at the time of registration. We will also disclose contact information to the 'users' of iPOTT website. 
  * As a 'Buyer or Seeker' you have to provide us with your Name, Designation, Company Address, E-mail, Size of Company, Value of software looking for etc. This information will be helpful to provide you with more information on the software / service you are looking for. The information is totally confidential. Only your contact details will be provided to the 'Promoter or Provider' if they have to contact you. 
  * You have to register in order to get full access to the information on iPOTT. The information submitted by you is totally confidential and will not be used for any other purpose other then the intended purpose. 

## Awareness

iPOTT provides this Online Privacy Statement to make you aware of our privacy policy, practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and from the bottom of every iPOTT.com, its subsidiaries' and affiliates' web pages. 

## What we collect

On some iPOTT web pages, you can order products or services, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected at these pages are name, contact and billing information, transaction, and credit card information. 

In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services (including registration), we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products, and more detailed contact preferences. Some electronic newsletters record anonymous data about articles you have expressed interest in. 

Some iPOTT.com web pages use cookies, a data analysis technique. To learn more, click here. How iPOTT uses cookies.

## How we use it 

iPOTT uses your information to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, to update you on service and benefits, and to personalize our web sites for you. Credit card numbers are used only for payment processing, fraud protection, and are not retained for other purposes. 

From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. At a minimum, we will always give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving such direct marketing or market research contact. We will also follow local requirements, such as allowing you to opt in before receiving unsolicited contact, where applicable. 

## Who we share it with 

iPOTT will not sell, rent, or lease your personally identifiable information to others. Unless we have your permission or are required by law, we will only share the personal data you provide online with other iPOTT entities and/or business partners who are acting on our behalf for the uses described in "how we use it". Such iPOTT entities and/or business partners, including those in the India and/or any other countries, are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality agreements.  
Data collected online may also be combined with information you provide when you register your ownership of iPOTT products. 

## Choice

iPOTT will not use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first letting you know and offering you a choice. As previously stated, we will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited direct marketing materials from us and we will do everything we can to honor such requests. Local country laws and policies are applied.

Your permission is always secured first, should we ever share your information with third parties that are not acting on our behalf and governed by our privacy policy. For example, as part of iPOTT's commitment to offering you choice, we enable you to make online purchases directly from us or through our resellers. When you choose our resellers, we inform you that your registration and shopping basket data is being transferred to the reseller you selected. This notice is important because when you choose to make online purchases through our resellers, use of your registration and shopping basket data by the reseller is then governed by their privacy policy. Local country laws and policies are applied. 

## Accuracy & Access 

iPOTT strives to keep your personally identifiable information accurate. We will provide you with access to your information, including making every effort to provide you with online access to your registration data so that you may view, update or correct your information at the iPOTT site where it was submitted. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections. To access your personally identifiable information, return to the web page where you originally entered it and follow the instructions on that web page. To opt-out of iPOTT contact, provide your name, email and/or address and relevant information about subscriptions or registrations you may have with iPOTT. This opt-out will cancel all marketing and support communication and newsletters, including software driver subscriptions. Certain areas of iPOTT's web sites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and through providing personally data. 

Links to third party web sites on the site are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the iPOTT site. iPOTT has not reviewed all of these third party sites and does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites, their content or their privacy policy. Thus, iPOTT does not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to this site, you do so at your own risk. 

## Security

iPOTT is committed to ensuring the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We use encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. Preventing credit card fraud is important to protect your personal financial data security . The Service gives you and iPOTT an extra level of protection to guard against credit card fraud. The secure data transfer and validation process between the Service and iPOTT is bound by contractual and confidentiality agreements.

We have appropriate security measures in place, to prevent unauthorized access or use of the information collected. We will also keep in secure place the literatures and the demo versions of the software to prevent accessibility to any third party. 

## Non Disclosure

We hereby declare that all information submitted by you is purely intended and is associated with the 'Listing' on our website iPOTT. We will not disclose any information to any other party for any other purpose. 

We also declare that the literatures are demo software provided to us will be retained by us only as a reference material. 

## Disclosure

Other than normal exchange of information, we may also disclose information in response to legal process or where we believe in good faith that the law requires it, for eg: - In response to a court order, subpoena or law and enforcement. 

## Oversight

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please [Contact us](http://www.ipott.com/jsp/contact.jsp). 

## How iPOTT uses cookies

A cookie is a piece of text asking permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. If you agree, then your browser adds the text in a small file. The purpose of a cookie is to help us analyze web traffic or let us know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow a web application to respond to you as an individual. By gathering and remembering information about your preferences, the web application can tailor its operation to your needs, likes and dislikes. For example, when you visit an electronic store, a cookie makes it easy to shop by allowing you to drop things into a shopping cart; the cart itself is not the cookie, the cookie is placed on your hard drive and keeps track of your cart versus others' in use at the same time. 

iPOTT uses traffic log cookies to identify what pages are being used and which ones aren't. This helps us aggregate and analyze data about web page traffic and make improvements to iPOTT.com web sites to better meet customer needs. In this case, iPOTT uses this information only for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. That is the case of many of our support and information-sharing pages and forums. Denial of a traffic log cookie should not prevent you from using one of these sites. 

A few iPOTT.com web sites use temporary cookies as part of the customer web navigation experience, tracking unique IDs for that particular web site session only. Examples are product registration sites. This cookie, by itself, only tells us that a previous iPOTT.com visitor has returned. If you deny the cookie, you can still use the site anonymously. When you register for the subscription service, it ensures that you are accurately identified and linked with your registration data.

Overall, cookies help us give you a better web site to use, by letting us monitor what's working and what isn't through site traffic analysis. iPOTT wants to be sure you understand that accepting a cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any personal information about you, other than the data you chose to share with us. This practice is strictly enforced. We know that a lot of people have concerns about cookies, but in talking with many of our customers, we believe that the benefit we both gain from their proper use is worthwhile. We value the relationships we have with our customers, so we respect these concerns. iPOTT works to continuously improve the iPOTT.com web experience and personal data privacy policy and practices. 

## Contact us

Please address all your queries and doubts pertaining to our privacy policy and security measures to [info@ipott.co.in](mailto:info@ipott.co.in)
